<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan Litzinger</title>
    <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nathan Litzinger</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://nlitz88.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:34:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nlitz88.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bird Detection With YOLOv7</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/birddetection/birddetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/birddetection/birddetection/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to this tutorial from TheCodingBug, I was able to use YOLOv7 to create a very primitive bird detection network. I scraped some generic Pennsylvania bird images, labelled them with a single &amp;ldquo;bird&amp;rdquo; class, and let YOLO work its magic overnight.
For only an evening&amp;rsquo;s worth of work, I am extremely happy with the results. No&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s REALLY promising. With the amount of footage I have recorded and can potentially label in time, I have no doubt that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to fine tune this model for our feeders and improve its recall even more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discrete Fourier Transform - Conceptual Overview and Practical Notes</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/dft/dft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 20:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/dft/dft/</guid>
      <description>This Spring (2022), I took my first signal processing class. One of the most interesting things we covered was the Fourier Transform, and more practically, the Discrete Time Fourier Transform.
I&amp;rsquo;m posting the PDF below as a reference for later projects, mainly to serve as a conceptual reminder of some of the concepts explaining the transform and how to do it. Though its covered on the Discrete Fourier Transform, the underlying principles are roughly the same for the DTFT (which we compute using fft).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Bird Feeder Live Stream</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/birdstream/birdstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 06:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/birdstream/birdstream/</guid>
      <description>As my Spring 2021 semester was nearing completion, I found myself looking for ways to &amp;ldquo;productively procrastinate&amp;rdquo; studying for finals. Like many others at the time, COVID had led my family to resurrect our bird feeders as another at-home distraction. While it was fun seeing all kinds of new birds emerge from our woods, I soon found myself in a predicament: I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the birds for the majority of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FS3 - My Mock File System</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/filesystem/filesystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 03:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/filesystem/filesystem/</guid>
      <description>As my Fall 2021 semester comes to a close, I made the final commits to perhaps one of the most interesting projects I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of stressing about thus far in school: building a file system.
Err&amp;ndash;okay, I won&amp;rsquo;t sit here and pretend that my classmates and I built out fully fledged filesystems ready to be thrown into Ubuntu for production. However, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite the point of this assignment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Chia Mine - Plotting With 10K SAS Drives</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/chia10kplotting/chia_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 20:58:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/chia10kplotting/chia_1/</guid>
      <description>As my fourth semester was just wrapping up, I was getting ready to take a few much needed weeks off before work and unwind just a little bit. Two days after my last final, however, I found out about Chia. Needless to say, I guess I never got to stop!
Fortunately for me and many other homelab and mining enthusiasts, farming Chia is a lot of fun. And by fun, I mean spending ludacris amounts of money on enterprise hardware that we would otherwise never have an excuse to buy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIPS Mini CPU - 5 Stage Pipeline in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/mipscpu/mipscpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 14:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/mipscpu/mipscpu/</guid>
      <description>As a conclusion to my computer organization course, our final project was to implement a five stage pipeline constructed in Verilog over an FPGA partially implementing the MIPS instruction set.
Abstract The following details the development of a five stage pipeline constructed on Xilinx&amp;rsquo;s Vivado in Verilog over an FPGA partially implementing the MIPS instruction set. In its current configuration, it supports only basic R-Format instructions like add, sub, and, or, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penn State New Kensington Research Expo - Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/blockchainproject/blockchainproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 23:52:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/posts/blockchainproject/blockchainproject/</guid>
      <description>Each year, Penn State New Kensington holds their Research and Student Engagement Expo where Penn State students like myself get to present their research findings to faculty and other students. Despite being held virtually as a consequence of the Pandemic, all of us seemed to persevere and come through with some really interesting projects and topics. You can find the main page for all of the projects here.
As a Sophomore in the Penn State New Kensington Honors Program, this was my year to participate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First QuinLED Dig Uno Project</title>
      <link>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/2020leds/2020leds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nlitz88.github.io/projects/2020leds/2020leds/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is more of just a retrospective post. I worked on this whole ordeal about a year ago and am only now finding the time to really document it. I just figured I&amp;rsquo;d throw up a few pictures of it and talk a little bit about it. Last winter break I became obsessed with individually addressable LEDs. More specifically, I was interested in controlling them. Soon enough, I found myself lost in the world of ESP based controllers and almost sank entirely into the home-assistant/home-automation world trying to find a good controller that</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
